All right we are alive...build twenty fifteen how you guys feeling about build.
...excited...with alex...last week I was at a conference in
russia like all the way the other side of the world the first question was is
pollens real the answer is yes,
it is indeed it is real and not holographic ...a real hollow
lengths this is one of the several hundred devices we broad
...and build this week where we're having a lot of the folks
...a experience follow...for themselves in
...of our lthree activities so what has the reaction
beard so floor for those people that I've been playing with so far
it has been pretty phenomenal people?
You know, communicate...and we
ask them beforehand about expectations we also ask them afterwards
where they thought and most people come out surprise
on it and they still come in with some amount of skepticism
...this is them okay, so, I saw it on stage was
...a screen I've seen a videos on the web is a really.
That good now and they come away usually with impression that, you know,
indeed everything that we have shown and...put up so
far is how the device...first-time I saw this...november I was in the same
cow mike this is to go to be real but it is
...and for most people that experience...you can describe it
have this sentence on the team that holographic experiences you must
kind of see them through ...yeah, right then
there's a materially different experience when you see
a hologram and...to your world because even when you see it on a video and
you see it...is not as immersive and core...as
...literally seeing something on top of your copy table on top next
your computer monitor or...one of those places right so here's the think by the
way ask questions where the question...but I want to ask this question because I'm a developer
...the universal windows platform you keep saying that
any built on top of that it's going to also work on...how is that
well so...runs understand the same windows
...online the universal api...that kuala
...primarily exposes antics advantage job is the api
sad the deals in terms of human understanding on one...ride...things like
days understanding where you're looking so, that if you're looking at holographic microphone as a
developer you have access to understand that a someone's trying to target
this object real or otherwise the gesture input a bit rights
...I can factor hands and I can actually say hey I'm looking at this holographic
object...click on...to selected those...api in speech
...the same engine behind the worked on a ok
that sits here the same extensibility so,...gesture invoice
...fundamentally apis...up across all of windows...and follow
...says and it took us...on the environment understanding side the other
half also those apis exists in every window stand
build from the little screens the big screens to nose-rings at all the apis set for
environment understanding for all world understanding really kind of
...big categories the first one is this idea of letting developers now
about...xyz?
Plane right in the world so that if I want to as a developer
...of holographic object on top of
the surface item literally say hey here's the coordinates...a would places here now
...wearing...I would see it if you're wearing...you would see it right and,
as a matter-of-fact, you know, anybody here would be able to share the same object in
the same xyz coordinate plane as everybody else that's
one piece of world understanding the next one is really spatial mapping
...ride this idea of being able to say hey, you know,...if I'm trying to
...holographic microphone on top of the stable I happen to know that...yeah,
you're right so,
I need to be able to...this environment in real-time and,
be able to in terms of developer apis essentially create a
...of it right...once I get a...of this environment coming in real-time I can
then project to it and I can say cable play something on top of it habit interests actor
be on top of the spatially map space.
That's quite remarkable all of the things that are happening all at
...there are you offloading this computation somewheres it all happening here how is...thursday
question dancers very carefully so, you can imagine that this the hollow...has,
you know, several different sensors for microphones are listening to the
...sound as well as the speaker wearing it...cameras that are looking and scanning
in map in this space to a number of otherwise
now you should imagine that at any point in time we
will have terabytes of data going in.
At the same time they need to be process for us to be able to understand the humans in the
environment's their and...this is more data than...you know,
traditional so ceased today would be able to process so what we've done is we've
developed a third co-processor we quality hp
you hard-up holographic processing unit and then we take all
of this sensor data we feed it to
our holographic processing unit it is responsible for doing all of the
human and world understanding on and then you get a very thin...
Going from the hp you over to your cpu
in cpu which uturn allows the entire, you know,
processing our of the cpu in
...to be dedicated to developers so that they can
create beautiful amazing...the...lines can work on a
...no companion devices working with that that's right one of the amazing
feats of the device is that it is a standalone fully and tethered holographic
computer...there are no markers...need to exist in the world around you there's
no external cameras they need to looking for us to be able to do this all the sensors are
in here and you also don't need a connection to abound or connection to
a pc all of latham infrastructure is actually in this beautiful part of
this...the device that's really cool is that when I first thought I thought they have to have
something else going what you've developed special hardware to take care of the understanding
...environment that's right that's...questions what part of the apis are specific to
hollow lens and what parts are windows...that's
a great question and the answer is there's no such thing as
...specific the parliaments follow lenses the first?
So, far only holographic computer out there but it doesn't mean that
will remain that, you know, for very long period of time matter-of-fact I hope that
in...so distant future adobe many such devices and then windows
holographic is the operating system that we put on which is just a
variant of windows stand behind so this is running windows stand all of the apis
for human and environment's understanding our part of windows in
this version of windows that we put on this device we call it windows holographic
rush that's remarkable...says any possibilities of poland's in
designed architecture...I'll tell ya I used to work as a
consulted for architects engineers and contractors
they're always working in three-d space.
Flatly absolutely so, we had...issued
both check out our...lands dot com website we have a great video
there by one of our announce partners yesterday the keynote
...is trimble...is a construction company and they have, you know,
lots of different softwares for architect's as well as, you know,
different things that they do in situation onsite as they're building a number of these
constructions they have been working for several months now with hollow
lens with windows holographic in my mind already
pushed forward that industry and pretty profound and meaningful ways
...all the way from how the architects see
they're work in three-d on top of my...I'm writing the
...this architecture work as...of these very expensive many tens of thousands of dollars much
...right and, now instead of building one changing something
...to build another one you can build one with the surrounding area and then project
...hologram on top of it this is a...for the
architects to communicate with appliance it's a faster way for people to be a visualize the work
...any number of things they coupled that with...of software they have on the
pc that allows them to keep track of different works any issues going on construction
...and then the people at the construction site also
then have hollow lenses and what that allows them to do is essentially no imagine, you know,
someone is in the construction site the
...overlay on the actual construction how the building supposed to look
...an issue on it a there is you know, I hear where you're supposed to be a door right they can
...or the architect and remotely in his off-base lookin' lc the
...what the hollow...on and then see what the other person is
...and they can synchronous...or asynchronous the have a conversation
...while they're apart they can immediately fix the issue and, you know,
document that are props they're tracking software and that's a really that's a good
site sort of feedback loop between the architect the contractor the engineer because,
you know, architects build these beautiful they're engineers like,
yeah, we can't make that and let me show you why but they could see why that's exactly correct when they get
what annotated and everybody has a much faster conversation
and they go from issue to resolution in a much more natural way because
of the end of the day we live in the real-world...as much as you can
that overlay all of this amazing digital content and pour it over the
real world at the end of the day your digital light becomes significantly more powerful
...you can see it in the context of the real-world and matter-of-fact this
trimble experience or...here I build it's one of the demos we have a follow
...for people to actually for the device on and try it all cool all right so manfred
...how can I start developing for
followings anticipation of it coming out people are excited they want to get started how they do that
the easiest thing I can say more generic thing I can say is just
...to know how to develop for essentially mobile three-d development
...the end of the day, you know, part of the journey the developer during for
all...is creating tools that are familiar to the skills the
developers already half-right and at the end of the day know if you think about your average,
you know, mobile three-d platform what are you trying to do at the end of the day
you have some physics and that three-d environment you have some matches in
that environment and you're trying to place digital assets on top of it right and there's several different
middleware pools that make that very easy for you to do...
go familiarize yourself this is a three-d world so this is not a tutti world it's not like putting, you know,
buttons on a farm but if you go get familiar with what it means to have a mobile
three-d development experience ...have a very easy and
transparent process to becoming a holographic developer dot that's great
...love the idea of using it was sky-high but how do you appear to the people on the other
ad they get to see you with pollens obscure your face it seems not the thing I liked about
...there was a video...where
the father was helping someone fitness I'm horrible at fixing things my wife is
...fixes...it'd be nice to sky to be able...how did that have the
demo work that's right so, you know, that is another demo we have here
...build for people...see its...holographic sky experience
...should imagine that like anything's scribe is, you know,
works on any number of different device and points so imagine for a minute that
bitty or referencing mom or dad are coming through tablet of
some sort of running windows it has...
and the beautiful thing is from that device what the hollow...adds to
it can actually see from the...eyes...a very being john...moment in your
line hindsight because at the end of the day person is moving around and you can see precisely where
...staring at and then as you can see through their eyes you can see this space
...do a three-d representation of it also that you can easily annotated
now as you annotate on this tablet with inc with touch with mouse with keyboard
what would happen is that annotation shows up to the where're of
...writing their world
...the right place I could say hey we'll make sure that this microphone is
turned around a little bit on my different device I can
...holographic will circle which makes it for me very simple to
...understand and having contact what I'm going to do so person in
...with seeing essentially a little
to be window with the face of the person on the other side so
if mom and dad on a tablet you just you can that can be on your
body walk around the house the thing is facing around or you can into the world I
can literally take your deed put it on a wall and say leave it there so that I know where your
...act and just, you know, keep track and back person on the other device
...from my...answer the question deliberately they don't see me right they see-through my eyes
and they can annotate input things and contacts now we have several experiences not this
...one this is a great examples
are mars experience that we've done in partnership with the folks at
...where you are in the same place with someone else in your all wearing
pollens and adapt point what we've done we've found to be very effective
...create a three-d advocate...that person right so you don't see that
...as a matter-of-fact and are video find both in
the trimble video this kind of a bluish avatar that's helping the person in
the construction site on the nasa one its or...person but the same
concept right so you...three-d avatar...the beautiful thing is that you
don't have on other platforms or devices you can actually know where the person is
...right so at this point like imagine you're taking a walk on mars your physically
sitting somewhere walking on mars and someone is physically sitting in a different location walking
in mars with you can look at a rock and you can say can you tell me about that
...person on the other side we'll see this orange...avatar
yours what they can see precisely where your gazing members...a demo yesterday
that's exactly correct and that context is everything and then
geologist on the other side...say yes I can tell you all about it but more interestingly
and that ling the meet point your direction to this...this ratification of it
is better and now you're having a very deep personal in context
conversation...even though you're not in the same space that's cool so here's a question
...it sounds kind of...functional question what happens...kitchens...opera leave it
...it up to the developer the short answer is it depends, yeah,
like if you're in windows holographic proper
...like any operating system we have a...now the shells
...by the operating system...where applications in general
exists...you saw darrin demonstrate onstage yesterday was that so,
at that point, you know, the user the customer the person that owns the hollow
...gets to choose where to place what right and I can say hey I place
this application this universal windows app of the video on this wall right I want to
...this calendar app on my kitchen-table those things are dan persisted
there...across fashions...time on until the you know,
customer comes in and says you...I don't like the little molly whether hologram
their group...deleted...now that's the context of the
...now let's say I'm a developer right and I
...windows universal app that's completely mercer
...say as an example are walk on mars
mass experience at that point persistence of...marcy?
In that room and where you place the...they say there across sessions of time or...of that is
the developers ic cool...another question will applications like
...and office provided interactive environment before just...platform and
...well ...great question-and-answer...work
...one first when I said that windows generally
has enabled human an environment understanding across all the
different operating systems that human part is portage this speech engine
...should imagine that you will be able to interact through speech ways...on hollow
...much like...doing your desktop much like to do...your phone much like you do
not with...about with speech on xbox the same speech engine and the same speech
apis across all of our devices follow
...included now on the office and it well, offices
a broad package with lots of different products...as part of office so,
sky paths a very specific as an example experience on
...lens that is completely redone and holographic author applications...you know,
outlook, outlook and all of the other,
you know, modern version of office experiences most artist flat two-d
...much like they're in showed onstage yesterday with...calendar and over time, you know?
They will change, yeah, that's really good we have some questions also coming from reddit we have a
...on...will connect be a part of windows holographic I
figured since connect doesn't stray too far away from pollens it would be considered part
of it that's a great question the idea of connect what
...is ultimately a set of sensors
that understand humansconnect understands humans in three different
...perspectives...human speech understands human identity and
...understands human gestures all of those things
exist across all versions of windows...identity has become the feature we
by nouns at...this year called windowsill up this idea that I can
...in front of a machines
...immediately be logged in securely and safely
right and the authenticated with payment instruments
and enterprise resources associated with right so that has
existed started and connect many years ago it's now a different
feature that has shown up on all windows and devices
...is the same thanks it started with
...now has become part time and we have talked about it on the gesture side of the world
that's just a piece of human understanding again right those api sat for understanding
...from a gesture perspective will exist in windows follow
...included from you plugging
...a connect that works and that supported...we love it that also exists with
...now intel real sense sensors as an example right on...of any number of
machines coming out this holiday with windows stan that will also work in
coexist in...as you get in front and you start gesturing so when I say
this is a super important point apis...environment understanding
exist across all versions of windows that's inclusive of all of the work that
started on our team command that's awesome that's awesome that's kinda like that there's like the grandfather
...removing all these technologies for bringing together to make
...one of the beautiful things with windows, windows...has taken
a huge step forward in being able to consolidate all of
are different device and points in windows in one api surface
area with one universal store right ride so that as a developer
...immediately target
any number of devices with the same buying airing on and I can get
my same skills to be applied across anything I want and I can
tailor it david tread what a great keno this morning where he showed an example of writing
a universal app that could just work bonilla across all over device
endpoints from surface up to hollow...tablet phones and...boxes but then,
you know, as a developer he showed this was a great them...morning you showed how to tailor
...and how to as a developer do different device targeting to say if follow
...flapping let's make it three-d volumetric beautiful hologram right if
...boxing on this...his keno yesterday on the usa today...
that's nashville tags...show video instead so all of that was a huge
...enormous backed on windows
stand to essentially say, you know, a consolidate our device endpoints
...billion plus devices and make those billion
...devices available to developers with the consistent api sat
around and universal store
...in an environment understanding just a portion of that that's awesome a question romantically
how will hollowed be used in the medical industry...I mean this guy's a limited
...skies the limit and, again,
it's exciting am and we are partnering with me different people in
that space the one most excited about as the ones we had onstage
yesterday and it's a partnership we're doing with case western reserve university
...and the cleveland clinic where they're really looking at it at
least begin with in terms of the...education
right if you think about how most modern medicine is still pot in school
...some cadavers, yeah, and, it's a very difficult thing for people to, you know,
try to understand how human is alive by inspecting one that is
...and all of a sudden if you can put up holographic human in
their and understand the right proportion the right scale and...how something we
movements out something would,...looked through a person any number of things like
that is very powerful tool, yeah, that's cool so one of the other things and...for of
...that is questions you guys have a special camera to see what someone
...on holds how is that done that's right so,
...one of the things we struggled on for a very long-time?
Is how you get someone to experience...without...how do you talk about it how
do you announce something like this in a stage on a telecast when,
you know, people don't get...put one of these at home I would love to say hey everybody...a hollow
...on...holographic experience...
...well that doesn't work if you're sitting at home today so what we've done is essentially taken the
hollow...apart they can all the different components of it,
you know, bought four-k two-k camera and,
then mounted through that camera all of our different
sensors so when human puts this on you have to...looking through these holographic
...right with a lot of sensors that are keeping track of how this thing is moving and understanding the
humans and the...around...now imagine...and that, you know,
this very expensive forty-two camera four-k two-k camera is a human
eyeball I see now imagine I can put all of the same
sensors on top of it as a matter-of-fact if you look at,
you know, our camron stage kind of has a little...on top of it has little...because we know all
of our sensors are connected to it and now of a sudden...put this camron you're moving around,
you know, it's no different than a human moving around with the same environment and human understanding
...now if there's a person onstage wearing the device...seeing hologram
place over there if there's a camera person watching from the other side
is just like another human wearing...although...see the hologram
in the same place from their different viewpoints...the...person onstage is looking at
it...cameras looking at it and you get the beautiful, you know, slayer
...onstage aspects like the nasa demo...with someone
...now that's exactly correct and you could imagine that any number of people wearing
...share this map they share their environment understanding and the shared
...holographic experience so we just essentially say hey what would look...camera
with a hollow...the camera I ve just like...that's awesome
...have any kind of raves...depth perception built-in and is it easy to
access when developing applications that's a great question the answer is yes no,
range finding that stuff is not that cool there is a equivalent...put it this space
vacancy?
There's an equivalent of a connect in here think about it as
...next generation connect something that is significantly more powerful than
...that we have...today that's
...your super tiny mine and essentially worries about understanding the human
...that's the abstracting that's how I know where your gesturing so you can
select things that's also looking out and, you know,
not only understanding the world
but doing that surface mapping spatial mapping of the world
...mashup that comes back out for developers wax as is essentially, you know,
something that originally...from adapt sensor that's sitting on the
...now the other half of the question which is how
easy to access and the answer is it's not accessible you can access
the api sets for both human...environment understanding and
those things are abstracted by us but you don't get access to the actual sensors on for
a very simple reason we want to make sure that there is a...relativity devices that
exist...to make sure that even within this devices version from version, version to
...you keep the applications in the app store consistent you have that
promise
...customers consistent so then one of two things happens you can't innovate on it anymore because you're
break everybody right or you change things any break everybody
would want to either we both want to innovate and we don't want to break people so we
abstract all the sensors we don't give sensor access...developers but we give...experiences
the sensors are actually understanding because otherwise like there would be a paralysis
of experiences...don't know if you want to have a consistency and that's what...api gives you that's
...to some hardware all right so...js will be possible take a video recording with
hons and have a hologram read...that feature we call it makes reality capture
one of the things that there's a photo video camera here as well and,
not only...photo video camera...can take stills and videos of the real world much
...of your consumer products and today but because it's a hollow
...we can intercept that feed into essentially the same thing we do on
stage so that stage when you see, you know, on a screen you see
the screen with the hologram on top of it right that's just a mix reality capture coming from
hollow...has come from the person caring it now the camron stages
...much high-resolution camera right this is not a four-k two-k
cameras here but you get that same experience on writing is one of the and the ability to a
mix reality capture and easily sharing...of your social media
sites is something we are actually super excited about one of our one-to-one experiences
for people...is hollows studio...studio one of the things we have people do
...a...is essentially poured three-d pony that they build on top
account when you get another human to kind of come back...and they take...makes reality capture a bit so
they can see that feature inaction it superfund I can't wait to see all source
...social media light up with shorts videos instills of
hologram I think it's really cool thing I'm pretty excited it seems like we're kinda
running low on time so here's a very serious question very
...answer so you have some really cool here...we got a homelands with your hair on
the side like a special addition alec skip main poland's here
...you know, we have along the feature list to go through...that to the bottom ...
now find the...version sq of how the
...in a theater near you announced hear-hear versions
...of the holland...so much is there anything else you want to tell developers out there now work
cited were excited to interact with developers your build and we hold
...now a lot of people come by to play would love...back there's
...of feedback...the last hundred so days as we've announced it and we love
...the team thrives on it there's a lot of
for us to learn and ultimately this holographic journey is one we're
going-to have to do together all of us right we started the developer journey for hollow
...here and build yesterday and
is only now beginning which means as we proceed forward into this
...into ultimately launching the device I look forward to all the feedback
is going to be exciting loss to learn lots to do are pretty excited to thanks so much
...some time with us alex on this thanking
...and where to go break and we'll go to the next...you guys were watching the like this?